<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://earnstudios.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://earnstudios.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-02-21T14:02:40+00:00</updated><id>http://earnstudios.com/</id><title>EARN Studios</title><subtitle>We are an entrepreneurial creative agency, our mission is to earn brand love with brave clients</subtitle><entry><title>Five more reasons why happy staff are good for business</title><link href="http://earnstudios.com/blog/5-more-reasons-why-happy-staff-are-good-for-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five more reasons why happy staff are good for business" /><published>2016-06-22T12:49:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-22T12:49:00+00:00</updated><id>http://earnstudios.com/blog/5-more-reasons-why-happy-staff-are-good-for-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://earnstudios.com/blog/5-more-reasons-why-happy-staff-are-good-for-business/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;as-a-result-of-the-success-of-top-5-reasons-why-happy-staff-are-good-for-business-we-thought-wed-give-you-5-more-reasons-why-focusing-on-the-happiness-of-your-team-can-translate-into-big-business-benefits&quot;&gt;As a result of the success of ‘Top 5 reasons why happy staff are good for business’, we thought we’d give you 5 more reasons why focusing on the happiness of your team can translate into big business benefits.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;better-health&quot;&gt;Better Health&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is growing evidence that happiness may protect against ill-heath and the risk of disease by strengthening our immune system, helping us deal with stress, pain, indulge in health-promoting behaviours (such as exercising and eating healthily) and lead to a longer life (1).  One of the most famous studies in Positive Psychology links positive emotion in early life to longevity six decades later (2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness has been found to predict lower levels of the stress hormone cortisol as well as lower heart rate and blood pressure three years later (3).  In another study, Psychology Professor Sheldon Cohen and colleagues found that people who were happy, pleased or relaxed were less likely to catch colds and experienced fewer symptoms of illness compared to those who were unhappy, anxious or depressed (4).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At work, happy employees take fewer sick days (5)  and what’s more, in line with the ‘contagion effect’, employees in one study were more likely to rate themselves as happy and healthy if their CEO was also happy! (6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;greater-persistence-and-ability-to-overcome-obstacles&quot;&gt;Greater persistence and ability to overcome obstacles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true that unremittingly cheerful people can be irritating especially when they insist that the difficulty you’re facing isn’t a problem but an opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a recovering pessimist myself, it’s doubly annoying to discover that optimists are more flexible in their thinking and often show greater persistence in the face of a challenge! (7)  Every business leader wants staff who aim high and who are willing to strive for the very best results. Because happiness is linked to persisting with difficult goals, it makes sense to focus on happiness at work, and finding ways to increase it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since happiness is a subjective experience, what works will vary from person to person, although there are key themes which most people will share, such as strong relationships and meaningful, motivating work which plays to their strengths (as well as fair terms and conditions). Learning about happiness and its complexities is a step in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;happiness-is-linked-to-greater-resilience-and-undoes-negative-emotions&quot;&gt;Happiness is linked to greater resilience and ‘undoes’ negative emotions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Positive Psychology research also suggests that there is a link between how happy we feel and our resilience – in other words our ability to overcome the inevitable disappointments, difficulties or set-backs in life and, if we have learned something valuable from the experience, to bounce back and be in a stronger, more resourceful position as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quotation attributed to the philosopher Friedrich Nietzsche &lt;em&gt;“that which does not kill us, makes us stronger”&lt;/em&gt; is very fitting here. In her research, Professor Barbara Fredrickson found that positive emotions enhanced both psychological and physical resilience (8). She referred to this as  “undoing” the negative emotions associated with difficult events and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the constant change that we all have to accommodate at work, with new initiatives, new bosses and colleagues, new products and services, new technology and processes, changes of strategic direction, new competitors and so on, resilience is a skill that every employee needs in abundance. Whilst it’s true that some people are predisposed to be more resilient than others (in the same way that some are more optimistic than others), fortunately, resilience skills can be trained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;happy-people-are-more-helpful&quot;&gt;Happy people are more helpful&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychology research shows a strong association between happiness, health and longevity on the one hand and altruistic emotions and pro-social behaviours on the other. Happy people tend to be more helpful and volunteer more. Like other benefits associated with happiness, it’s a two-way street: if you’re feeling happy you’re more likely to willingly provide social support and show compassion to others, and engaging in kind and helpful behaviour will boost your happiness (9).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since business success relies completely on day-to-day co-operation, collaboration and goodwill between colleagues, increasing the level of happiness in the company is one way to maximise this. And just think how much more satisfying the working day is when you help others get out of a tight spot and you know you can rely on them in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;happiness-is-linked-to-higher-customer-service-ratings&quot;&gt;Happiness is linked to higher customer service ratings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever had to ring a customer services department to resolve a problem with a product or service you’ve bought, you’ll know that speaking to a pleasant, friendly and good-humoured employee can immeasurably improve your experience, make the whole process easier and ensure that your conversation doesn’t escalate into an altercation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you won’t be surprised to find that in a study of customer service departments, researchers have found that employees who score high in life satisfaction are significantly more likely to receive high ratings from customers (10).  It’s highly likely that your organisation’s training covers conventional customer services skills such as active listening, communication, product/service knowledge and rapport-building, but does it look at individual happiness, what it means and how to increase it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there it is, in a nutshell: happiness is not only good for you and your employees it’s also good for your business.  Yes, work can be stressful, challenging and difficult at times, but it can also be fun, fulfilling and rewarding, and when it is, you’ll be doing your best work. Ironically, making happiness at work a priority can be tough.  But we’ve now given you 10 evidence-based reasons (5 in this article and 5 previously) why you need to take happiness seriously.  All you have to do now is take that first step. At the EARN Happiness School we’re passionate about making work your happy place so do get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article written by Bridget Grenville-Cleave&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bridget Grenville-Cleave has more than 20 years of experience in private and public sectors developing and delivering evidenced-based positive psychology training programmes, workshops, and CPD. She consults and coaches in the corporate, education and health sectors to enhance well-being, engagement and performance. She is also the leading consultant at EARN Happiness School and co-creator of How’s Your Day? app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more great info on the science of happiness and how to create happiness at work and in life be sure to follow our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/how%27s-your-day-?trk=biz-brand-tree-co-name&quot;&gt;How’s Your Day&lt;/a&gt; page on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) Burton, C. M., &amp;amp; King, L. A. (2004). The health benefits of writing about intensely positive experiences. Journal of research in personality, 38(2), 150-163.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) Danner, D., Snowdon, D. &amp;amp; Friesen, W. (2001). Positive emotions in early life and longevity: Findings from the nun study. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 80(5), 804-813.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(3) Steptoe, A. &amp;amp; Wardle, J. (2005). Positive affect and biological function in everyday life. Neurobiology of aging, 26(1), 108-112.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(4) Cohen, S., Doyle, W., Turner, R., Alper, C. &amp;amp; Skoner, D. (2003). Emotional style and susceptibility to the common cold. Psycho- somatic Medicine, 65, 652–657.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(5) Gil, K., Carson, J., Porter, L., Scipio, C., Bediako, S. &amp;amp; Orringer, E. (2004). Daily mood and stress predict pain, health care use, and work activity in African American adults with sickle-cell disease. Health Psychology, 23, 267–274.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(6) Foster, J. B., Hebl, M. R., West, M., &amp;amp; Dawson, J. (2004, April). Setting the tone for organizational success: The impact of CEO affect on organizational climate and firm-level outcomes. Paper presented at the 17th annual meeting of the Society for Industrial and Organizational Psychology, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(7) There are benefits associated with ‘defensive pessimism’ but that’s for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(8) Fredrickson, B. L. (2003). The value of positive emotions. American scientist, 91(4), 330-335.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(9) Post, S. G. (2005). Altruism, happiness, and health: It’s good to be good. International journal of behavioral medicine, 12(2), 66-77. Lu, L., &amp;amp; Argyle, M. (1991). Happiness and cooperation. Personality and Individual Differences, 12(10), 1019-1030.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(10) George, J. &amp;amp; Bettenhausen, K. (1990). Understanding prosocial behavior, sales performance, and turnover: A group-level analysis in a service context. Journal of Applied Psychology, 75(6), 698-709.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>bridget_grenville-cleave</name></author><summary>As a result of the success of ‘Top 5 reasons why happy staff are good for business’, we thought we’d give you 5 more reasons why focusing on the happiness of your team can translate into big business benefits.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://earnstudios.com/uploads/five-more-reasons.jpg" /></entry><entry><title>The Future Marketer’s Toolkit: what all marketers need to know</title><link href="http://earnstudios.com/blog/the-future-marketers-toolkit-what-all-marketers-need-to-know/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future Marketer’s Toolkit: what all marketers need to know" /><published>2016-05-20T12:50:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-20T12:50:00+00:00</updated><id>http://earnstudios.com/blog/the-future-marketers-toolkit-what-all-marketers-need-to-know</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://earnstudios.com/blog/the-future-marketers-toolkit-what-all-marketers-need-to-know/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-almost-redundant-to-say-the-digital-landscape-has-changed-drastically-in-the-last-decade-but-why-hasnt-the-marketers-toolkit-evolved-with-it-they-say-you-cant-use-old-tools-for-todays-job-and-be-in-business-tomorrow-and-we-agree&quot;&gt;It’s almost redundant to say the digital landscape has changed drastically in the last decade, but why hasn’t the marketer’s toolkit evolved with it? They say you can’t use old tools for today’s job and be in business tomorrow and we agree.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EARN Founder Jamal Benmiloud (former Head of Marketing for Red Bull and VP of Marketing at Monster Energy) and Stephen Taylor (former CMO of Samsung and Global Brand Director of Proctor and Gamble) have engaged in a series of frank, unscripted chats that address this and other key marketing challenges that the industry is currently facing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;issue-number-one-the-marketers-toolkit&quot;&gt;Issue number one: the marketer’s toolkit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If marketers want more effective means of getting their message in front of their target audiences and enticing these audiences to engage with their content and brands, marketers may need to upgrade their toolkits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-the-marketers-toolkit&quot;&gt;What is the marketer’s toolkit?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephen Taylor:&lt;/strong&gt; The marketer’s toolkit is sort of simple, but we do our best to overcomplicate it. First, you start with the “who”. Who are you targeting with the product or proposition you’ve got? You need to be super-clear on who they are and more importantly, who they are not. What types of media are they interacting with? Which are the ones they’re not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second piece is the “what”. Some people call the “what” the concept or the value proposition. It’s the products, services and brand values you’re offering the consumer that make you distinct and differentiated and stand out from the rest. It’s linked back to the people you’ve identified as your “who”; the prime people you’re targeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there is the “how.” You probably need to be more robust about what your business model is. Is there a digital disruption or other disruption that could influence it? This needs to be thoroughly thought through, more so than in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last bit, which I think is the most complicated for people today is how you get your message to your “who.” What is your method for getting your message to the consumers that’s going to add all of these elements together giving your target audience the right message about who you are, what you stand for and what you’ve got to offer that is different. I think this is the element that’s seen the most dramatic change. It’s the one that needs aggressive re-examination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-does-the-future-marketers-toolkit-look-like&quot;&gt;What does the future marketer’s toolkit look like?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jamal Benmiloud:&lt;/strong&gt; Twenty years ago, the “how” was connecting with audiences through television, radio and print ads. Now, people just aren’t talking about advertisements in the office or at school. It just doesn’t work in the same way. Now it’s about creating platforms or creating experiences for the same effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are brands that have worked out that digital for them is about partnering. It’s thinking: “Right, what can we invent together and work together to do?” which is way more powerful an idea than just taking your offline business and plastering it in the online world. The brands of the future are the ones that understand that. Before, it was all about buying, whereas in the future it’s about partnering. In essence your digital product experience IS your brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-obstacle-do-you-think-marketers-need-to-prepare-for-in-the-nearby-future&quot;&gt;What obstacle do you think marketers need to prepare for in the nearby future?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jamal Benmiloud:&lt;/strong&gt; Ad blocking. All it takes is for people to block marketing. You look at Brazil and there are certain cities, like São Paulo, that have decided: no more OOH advertising. There is something about the rise of ad blocking that’s asking the marketing industry what are we doing to make sure we’re actually adding value to people’s lives, and that’s driving us to create welcoming experiences that people want to engage with rather than block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephen Taylor:&lt;/strong&gt; I think that’s going to be absolutely crucial. I think one of the irritations and the downsides of marketing via mobile device and digital is how intrusive it is; how many pop-ups you get that you don’t want. I’ve suddenly got all of these notifications that say my Moshi Monster needs feeding and I didn’t even know I had a Moshi Monster. All that stuff will be the downfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve read what Jamal and Stephen had to say, we’d love to hear your thoughts. Do you think the marketer’s toolkit is overdue for an upgrade or do you think it’s timeless? Get in touch and let us know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you like this blog and want more like it be sure to share it on LinkedIn via our InShare button.xw&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow EARN on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/earn-media-limited&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jamal_benmiloud</name></author><summary>It’s almost redundant to say the digital landscape has changed drastically in the last decade, but why hasn’t the marketer’s toolkit evolved with it? They say you can’t use old tools for today’s job and be in business tomorrow and we agree.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://earnstudios.com/uploads/future-marketers-toolkit.jpg" /></entry><entry><title>Why I quit the best job in the world to launch my own business</title><link href="http://earnstudios.com/blog/why-i-quit-the-best-job-in-the-world-to-launch-my-own-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I quit the best job in the world to launch my own business" /><published>2016-04-11T12:51:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-04-11T12:51:00+00:00</updated><id>http://earnstudios.com/blog/why-i-quit-the-best-job-in-the-world-to-launch-my-own-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://earnstudios.com/blog/why-i-quit-the-best-job-in-the-world-to-launch-my-own-business/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-worry-this-wont-be-a-love-story-to-myself-but-with-that-said-i-think-its-important-for-you-to-know-a-bit-of-my-background-before-i-get-into-the-meat-of-this-blog&quot;&gt;Don’t worry; this won’t be a love story to myself. But with that said, I think it’s important for you to know a bit of my background before I get into the meat of this blog.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left Monster Energy as VP of Marketing, a position I had secured after my success as the Head of Marketing for Red Bull, to launch my own entrepreneurial creative agency, EARN. Did I leave Monster because I was unhappy? Not at all. I actually appreciated the freedom Monster gave me to start with a blank piece of paper, build a marketing team from scratch, develop processes and create a culture from nothing. But after five years at Monster, I just felt it was time for me to move on and to open up space for my amazing team to progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m not trying to make it sound like it was a zen process for me because it wasn’t. I still sometimes reflect and think: “Am I mad in making this choice?” But then when I look back at my career, it’s apparent that I’m the kind of person that’s about building things. And after my runs at Red Bull and Monster, I felt it was time to start building again, but this time for myself. It was time for me to build my own team, my own culture and my own processes that are centred on my own values. I wanted to take the innovative model of marketing we’d developed at Monster and Red Bull and share it with other brands. You can read more about that model in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Brand-Love-Build-Worth-Talking-ebook/dp/B00VBPBU1G&quot;&gt;Brand Love&lt;/a&gt;, a book I co-authored with Graham Brown and Paul O’Shannessey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve got my background (and my shameless book plug) out of the way, let’s dive into the topic at hand: Why did I quit the best job in the world to launch my own business?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t leave Monster because I wanted to escape corporate life. I had a great boss, but I wanted to be in control. I wanted to be my own boss and I wanted to be able to make decisions that reflected my values, like spending more time with my family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the time came to leave Monster, I tried to leave quietly, but contrary to my plans my team decided to surprise me by taking me out for dinner. I can remember sitting at the dinner being so overwhelmed by the thought that I was leaving. It was such an intense moment. It wasn’t that I was having any fear; it was just the enormity of what I was attempting to accomplish. I was on a new road where I absolutely had no real experience of building my own business or running an agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also an element of leaving something behind. At Red Bull and Monster, I was very fortunate to attend and produce some amazing events with amazing people like Formula 1 or the Red Bull Air Race. It was an incredibly rewarding and exciting time. However, I was also beginning to feel that I had grown past that period of my life. I was at Red Bull and Monster in my 20’s and early 30’s, and that was a good 10 years of my life. Now, I’d much rather have more simple experiences and more time with my children, wife and extended family and friends because the downside of corporate life is obviously it takes so much of your time away. So I didn’t really see leaving as giving up. I saw it as the right step into an exciting new phase of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days of leaving Monster, once I started to actually talk about being the founder of EARN and was able to land a few client meetings, it was exhilarating. It was so exciting. I felt free - like the whole world was an opportunity. I felt creative; like I did in those early years of starting each job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m actually writing this blog from an office I built in my garden. EARN has an office in London for the team where we work together and work with clients, but when I don’t need to go into town, I can just walk across the garden and work from here. And that’s not to say I have a simple easy life now. I would say that I work just as hard and probably longer hours than I did at Monster. And even when I’m with my family, I’m thinking about the business, but by being in control, it’s a totally different kind of energy. I now have the option to say no to things that don’t match up with the kind of life that I’m building for my family or for the wider team at EARN. At EARN we ultimately do work that we’re really proud of. We create strategy and ideas that get the world talking about our clients’ brands and products. Having such an ambitious daily goal means I’ve managed to create a job I can see myself doing for the rest of my life, which I’m very grateful for.
&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/launch-my-own-business.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;launch-my-own-business.jpg&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;em&gt;Jamal hard at work in his garden office (designed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ginageoghegan.com/&quot;&gt;Gina Geoghegan&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My advice to those who are thinking about taking this kind of leap of faith is to remember that there’s nothing to stop anyone from building a business these days with very little resources. I think that if you do have the energy to start your own enterprise, you can dream big, but just start small. At EARN, we often say: “It’s better to dream big, and start small, and actually do 1% of the journey than nothing at all.” If your dream is to start an agency, just aim to do that 1%, and then see where that takes you and what conversations that brings, and meet as many people as you can, and learn from as many people as you can because that’s ultimately the greatest currency that you can get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve heard from me, I’d like to hear from you. Are you in a dream job, but considering starting your own business? What do you think of my decision to leave Monster and launch EARN?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you know anyone that might find some motivation, encouragement or clarity from this blog please share it with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow EARN on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/earn-media-limited&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jamal_benmiloud</name></author><summary>Don’t worry; this won’t be a love story to myself. But with that said, I think it’s important for you to know a bit of my background before I get into the meat of this blog.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://earnstudios.com/uploads/launch-my-own-business.jpg" /></entry><entry><title>Top five reasons why happy staff are good for business</title><link href="http://earnstudios.com/blog/top-5-reasons-why-happy-staff-are-good-for-business-why-happiness-at-work-is-a-serious-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top five reasons why happy staff are good for business" /><published>2016-03-31T12:52:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-31T12:52:00+00:00</updated><id>http://earnstudios.com/blog/top-5-reasons-why-happy-staff-are-good-for-business-why-happiness-at-work-is-a-serious-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://earnstudios.com/blog/top-5-reasons-why-happy-staff-are-good-for-business-why-happiness-at-work-is-a-serious-business/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;happiness-at-work-is-not-rocket-science-the-research-findings-on-what-makes-people-happy-at-work-are-for-the-most-part-surprisingly-ordinary-having-good-work-recognised-getting-positive-feedback-and-feeling-respected-all-make-a-difference-to-how-people-feel-about-their-work-so-you-could-say-that-being-a-great-boss-is-simple-although-not-necessarily-easy-to-do&quot;&gt;Happiness at work is not rocket science; the research findings on what makes people happy at work are, for the most part, surprisingly ordinary. Having good work recognised, getting positive feedback and feeling respected all make a difference to how people feel about their work, so you could say that being a great boss is simple (although not necessarily easy) to do.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why should you care if your staff are happy at work or not? Well, there is growing evidence from the field of Positive Psychology that aside from just feeling good, being happy at work has significant business benefits and since we are always looking for new ways to have the edge over our competitors and be more successful organisations, could a focus on happiness be what you’ve been waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;higher-creativity&quot;&gt;Higher creativity&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a bit of a myth that high pressure, negativity and fear in the workplace give rise to high achievement, particularly in roles which require creativity. In fact, research by Professor Theresa Amabile and colleagues at Harvard Business School (1)  suggests that people are more likely to come up with creative ideas if they’re in a good mood. What’s more, there is a carry-over effect meaning that being in a good mood today also contributes to your creativity and original thinking tomorrow. 
Studies carried out by Positive Psychology expert, Barbara Fredrickson, suggest that positive emotions do more than just make us feel good, they also enable us to function better. It seems that people who feel good also think more creatively. She concluded that &amp;gt;“…when people feel good, their thinking becomes more creative, integrative, flexible and open to information”. (2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if your organisation could benefit from more creative, original or innovative thinking and ideas, it makes good business sense to find ways to enhance the level of happiness amongst your employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;better-relationships&quot;&gt;Better relationships&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relationships and happiness are interconnected – when we feel happy we find it easier to reach out and make connections with others and having people around us who we like, trust and can rely on boosts our well-being (3)  and our intrinsic motivation (4). In fact, relationships are so important to us that they feature in many different models of human well-being (5).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being happier at work also leads to better relationships and even if you are more of an introvert than a team player at work, there are very few roles which couldn’t be enhanced by stronger connections with others. Even relatively solitary jobs like writing, researching or data analysis benefit from the input of other people at some stage in the process. Having a pool of supportive friends, colleagues and acquaintances to call on for advice, help or ideas, as well as the personal skills and abilities to manage those relationships effectively are essential. There is evidence from Positive Psychology that feeling happy contributes to better relationships as well as vice versa (6)  and that workplace friendships lead to greater engagement (7).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;greater-engagement&quot;&gt;Greater Engagement&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engagement has become a real buzzword around organisations in the past decade. Being ‘engaged’ at work generally means that you are fully absorbed by and enthusiastic about what you do, and are happy to go the extra mile for your employer. Employee engagement has a huge range of business benefits: amongst other things it’s linked to reduced absenteeism, higher retention, greater effort and productivity, increased sales, turnover and profitability and enhanced customer satisfaction (8).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, business leaders the world over want to know the secret of increasing levels of employee engagement. Given the Positive Psychology evidence that happiness and engagement are linked, psychologists Martin Stairs and Martin Galpin suggest that boosting happiness at work is key. So, if you want your staff to be more engaged, focus on their happiness!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;better-problem-solving&quot;&gt;Better problem-solving&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experiencing positive emotions (such as delight, interest and contentment) develops our awareness and capacity to think and behave in different ways, which Professor Barbara Fredrickson calls the ‘broaden and build’ effect. In other words, feeling positive on a frequent basis broadens our outlook and over time builds enduring mental, physical, social and intellectual resources, including our ability to solve problems (9).  So, high-quality problem-solving isn’t just dependent on our level of experience and our ability to engage in left-brain, analytical thinking. It relies on us feeling good too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;better-decision-making&quot;&gt;Better decision-making&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our work lives and business outcomes are enhanced when we make good decisions. As with problem-solving, the quality of our decision-making depends to a great extent on our expertise in a given field, our knowledge and our experience. But interestingly, research in the domains of psychology and neuroscience have revealed that positive emotions also influence the decision-making process. What we now know is that our happiness is not peripheral or inconsequential, it actually plays an important, integral role in shaping how we think, plan and make decisions (10).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above, happiness at work isn’t only about fair terms and conditions, although they have a part to play. With the amount of knowledge and experience around now in the field of Positive Psychology, and inspirational business initiatives like the EARN Happiness School, there is an enormous amount that you can do to influence the level of happiness in your organisation and reap the combined individual and business benefits. If you care about yourself, your business and your staff, surely it’s a no-brainer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bridget Grenville-Cleave has more than 20 years of experience in private and public sectors developing and delivering evidenced-based positive psychology training programmes, workshops, and CPD. She consults and coaches in the corporate, education and health sectors to enhance well-being, engagement and performance. She is also the leading consultant at EARN Happiness School and co-creator of How’s Your Day? app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more great info on the science of happiness and how to create happiness at work and in life be sure to follow our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/how%27s-your-day-?trk=biz-brand-tree-co-name&quot;&gt;How’s Your Day&lt;/a&gt; page on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amabile, T., Barsade, S., Mueller, J. &amp;amp; Staw, B. (2005). Affect and creativity at work. Administrative science quarterly, 50(3), 367-403.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fredrickson, B. (2003, p333). The value of positive emotions: The emerging science of positive psychology is coming to understand why it’s good to feel good. American scientist, 91(4), 330-335; Fredrickson, B. (2003). Positive emotions and upward spirals in organizations. Positive organizational scholarship, 163-175.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fredrickson, B. (2003, p333). The value of positive emotions: The emerging science of positive psychology is coming to understand why it’s good to feel good. American scientist, 91(4), 330-335; Fredrickson, B. (2003). Positive emotions and upward spirals in organizations. Positive organizational scholarship, 163-175.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ryan, R.M. &amp;amp; Deci, E.D. (2001) On happiness and human potentials: A review of research on hedonic and eudaimonic well-being. Annual Review of Psychology, 52, 141-66.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nef (2008). Five Ways to Wellbeing. Report prepared by the new economics foundation (nef) for the UK Government Foresight Project, Mental Capital and Wellbeing; Seligman, M. (2011). Flourish: A visionary new understanding of happiness and well-being. New York: Free Press; Ryff, C. (1989). Happiness is everything, or is it? Explorations on the meaning of psychological well-being. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 6, 1069-81.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diener, E. &amp;amp; Biswas-Diener, R. (2008). Happiness: Unlocking the mysteries of psychological wealth. Oxford, UK: Blackwell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rath, T. (2006). Vital friends. New Your, NY: Gallup Press.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stairs, M. &amp;amp; Galpin, M. (2013). Positive engagement: From employee engagement to workplace happiness. In A. Linley, S. Harrington &amp;amp; N . Garcea (Eds.). The Oxford handbook of positive psychology and work (pp155-172). Oxford, UK: Oxford University Press.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fredrickson, B. (2001). The role of positive emotions in positive psychology. American Psychologist 56 (3): 218–226. Fredrickson, B. (2003). The value of positive emotions: The emerging science of positive psychology is coming to understand why it’s good to feel good. American Scientist, 91, 330-335.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Isen, A.M. &amp;amp; Labroo, A.A. (2003). Some ways in which positive affect facilitates decision making and judgment. In S. Schneider &amp;amp; J. Shanteau (Eds.) Emerging perspectives on judgment and decision research (pp365-393). Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>jamal_benmiloud</name></author><summary>Happiness at work is not rocket science; the research findings on what makes people happy at work are, for the most part, surprisingly ordinary. Having good work recognised, getting positive feedback and feeling respected all make a difference to how people feel about their work, so you could say that being a great boss is simple (although not necessarily easy) to do.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://earnstudios.com/uploads/top-five-reasons.jpg" /></entry><entry><title>Brand Love Model</title><link href="http://earnstudios.com/blog/brand-love-model/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brand Love Model" /><published>2016-03-08T12:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-08T12:55:00+00:00</updated><id>http://earnstudios.com/blog/brand-love-model</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://earnstudios.com/blog/brand-love-model/">&lt;p&gt;At EARN, we believe that there are three key drivers of brand love: &lt;strong&gt;people, culture and metrics&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s nice if you can get it right but it’s not always integral to business success. However, taking on the learnings from our experience at Red Bull and Monster Energy, we know that your people &lt;strong&gt;ARE&lt;/strong&gt; your most powerful marketing platform. It was the people and the culture of these organisations that made them the successes you see today. If you start to treat marketing as a mind-set, not a department, then you will unlock something very powerful within your organisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once you’ve got the people and culture bit right, you can start to turn your attention to metrics. How are you evaluating success for your business? Time and time again, we talk to brands to try to get them to reassess the way they are viewing reporting and measurement. This has a fundamental effect on the way your business operates and performs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our belief is that, more often than not, brands should be investing their time and attention in establishing more quality over quantity metrics (NPS, engagement and recommendation) because if you get these right then the quantity metrics and sales will come… and will be much more sustainable in the long-term. If you focus first and foremost on sales and performance, then you will only allow your teams to be thinking with a very short-termist view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that’s our humble view but we’d love to hear your thoughts… is there anything you would add or change? What has your experience been around the importance of people, culture and marketing metrics?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/brand-love.svg&quot; alt=&quot;brand-love.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow EARN on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/earn-media-limited&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jamal_benmiloud</name></author><summary>At EARN, we believe that there are three key drivers of brand love: people, culture and metrics.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://earnstudios.com/uploads/brand-love.jpg" /></entry><entry><title>Top five quotes from Brand Love as voted by readers</title><link href="http://earnstudios.com/blog/top-five-quotes-from-brand-love-as-voted-by-readers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top five quotes from Brand Love as voted by readers" /><published>2016-02-26T12:58:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-26T12:58:00+00:00</updated><id>http://earnstudios.com/blog/top-five-quotes-from-brand-love-as-voted-by-readers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://earnstudios.com/blog/top-five-quotes-from-brand-love-as-voted-by-readers/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-checked-amazon-to-find-out-the-quotes-that-readers-loved-most-from-our-brand-love-book-here-are-the-top-five-principles-according-to-you&quot;&gt;We checked Amazon to find out the quotes that readers loved most from our Brand Love book. Here are the ‘top five’ principles, according to you:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What matters is not what you make for your customers, but what you mean to them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If customers like you, be afraid. If customers like you, you might as well be invisible. People only recommend the brands they love.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make a commitment to stop going after quantity and awareness and start going after quality and attention.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find the ecosystem where your brand can grow. Find your tribe, your home, the place where you belong. Grow your brand there. Respect the dynamics and relationships and the ecosystem will look after you long-term.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Today, in ‘The Connection Economy’, everyone becomes a marketer by default. We’re not just talking about your customers. Think about how every single person in your business has become a marketer too. They all have their own networks; they all talk about your brand on a daily basis. Your marketing team, your call centre staff, your HR people, your CEO and your retail frontline – everyone is connected to everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download Brand Love: How to Build a Brand Worth Talking About Kindle Edition &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Brand-Love-Build-Worth-Talking/dp/1515201198/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1456246417&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=brand+love+book&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download the book via Amazon.com click &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Brand-Love-Build-Worth-Talking-ebook/dp/B00VBPBU1G/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1456246435&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;keywords=brand+love+book&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow EARN on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/earn-media-limited&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jamal_benmiloud</name></author><summary>We checked Amazon to find out the quotes that readers loved most from our Brand Love book. Here are the ‘top five’ principles, according to you:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://earnstudios.com/uploads/top-five-quotes.jpg" /></entry><entry><title>Monster beat Red Bull without spending a penny on advertising – what we’ve learned</title><link href="http://earnstudios.com/blog/monster-beat-red-bull-without-spending-a-penny-on-advertising-what-weve-learned/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monster beat Red Bull without spending a penny on advertising – what we’ve learned" /><published>2016-02-26T12:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-26T12:57:00+00:00</updated><id>http://earnstudios.com/blog/monster-beat-red-bull-without-spending-a-penny-on-advertising-what-weve-learned</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://earnstudios.com/blog/monster-beat-red-bull-without-spending-a-penny-on-advertising-what-weve-learned/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;monster-energy-drinks-is-well-a-monster-at-least-when-it-comes-to-marketing-monster-is-a-multi-billion-dollar-brand-that-at-times-has-been-more-profitable-per-employee-than-apple-monster-has-grown-its-market-share-from-nothing-to-a-market-lead-of-36-of-the-us-market-surpassing-its-rival-big-spender-red-bull-and-they-did-it-without-investing-a-penny-in-advertising-so-how-did-david-manage-to-beat-goliath-against-all-the-odds&quot;&gt;Monster Energy drinks is… well… a monster, at least when it comes to marketing. Monster is a multi-billion dollar brand that, at times, has been more profitable per employee than Apple. Monster has grown its market share from nothing to a market lead of 36% of the US market, surpassing its rival, big-spender Red Bull and they did it without investing a penny in advertising. So, how did David manage to beat Goliath against all the odds?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;a href=&quot;/do-companies-even-need-creative-agencies-in-the-connection-economy/&quot;&gt;traditional Ogilvy-era marketing&lt;/a&gt; focuses on resource intensive launches e.g. media buying, expensive campaigns and in-store promotions, which produce a tangible but very short-lived spike in sales and brand awareness. By contrast, Monster operates under a “waste not, want not” credo, investing all of its resources into cultivating Brand Love by converting their target market into fans who then go on to influence and recruit mainstream customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monster’s success lies in their ability to get the right people on board and to leverage those people’s own networks to create influence within the markets they target. In other words Monster found their ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ecosystems are natural, authentic networks based on real-world scenes. Each ecosystem has its own protocol, from the language used to the clothes worn. These networks possess a code often hidden to the outsider that reinforces social dynamics like who’s “in”, who’s “out” and who the key influencers are. Wherever your people already have networks is where you need to start building your brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Monster ecosystem lives within the Moto Cross, BMX and punk rock scenes. They realised this early on and made a concerted effort to curate a team of people who dwelled within these ecosystems. A pierced, tattooed chap wearing leather boots, a tattered Misfits vest and a baseball cap would stick out like a sore thumb at Pepsi, but for Monster he could be a pivotal brand touchpoint for fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At Monster, all of our guys walk the walk in action sports, punk rock music, partying, hangin’ with the girls and living life on the edge. Monster is way more than an energy drink. Led by our athletes, musicians, employees, distributors and fans, Monster is a lifestyle in a can!” — from the Monster Energy official Facebook page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s what EARN Founder and CCO, Jamal Benmiloud, formerly leading the marketing teams at both Red Bull and Monster, calls “story being” rather than “storytelling”. It’s building the brand from the inside, starting with its own people, growing an authentic brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brand Love isn’t reserved for hip, youth-oriented brands like Monster and Apple. It’s even possible if you’re operating in a less exciting, more restrictive sector like an airline. And you don’t need expensive campaigns or extensive redesigns to develop it. As a matter of fact, these traditional marketing techniques often fall apart after customers experience brands. If you want to cultivate Brand Love you have to start with your people. Who are your fans? Where is their ecosystem? Enlist a beachhead of employees and fans who love your idea, actively promote your brand and want a meaningful relationship with your company and then meet them where they live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow EARN on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/earn-media-limited&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jamal_benmiloud</name></author><summary>Monster Energy drinks is… well… a monster, at least when it comes to marketing. Monster is a multi-billion dollar brand that, at times, has been more profitable per employee than Apple. Monster has grown its market share from nothing to a market lead of 36% of the US market, surpassing its rival, big-spender Red Bull and they did it without investing a penny in advertising. So, how did David manage to beat Goliath against all the odds?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://earnstudios.com/uploads/monster-beat-redbull.jpg" /></entry><entry><title>Is happiness a key factor in high performing teams?</title><link href="http://earnstudios.com/blog/earn-happiness-school-is-happiness-a-key-factor-in-high-performing-teams/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is happiness a key factor in high performing teams?" /><published>2016-01-28T13:02:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-01-28T13:02:00+00:00</updated><id>http://earnstudios.com/blog/earn-happiness-school-is-happiness-a-key-factor-in-high-performing-teams</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://earnstudios.com/blog/earn-happiness-school-is-happiness-a-key-factor-in-high-performing-teams/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;on-monday-26-january-and-not-just-any-monday-the-monday-that-many-refer-to-as-blue-monday-earn-hosted-their-annual-earn-happiness-school--an-event-designed-to-enlighten-friends-clients-and-partners-on-the-subject-of-happiness-and-positive-psychology&quot;&gt;On Monday 26 January (and not just any Monday, the Monday that many refer to as Blue Monday), EARN hosted their annual EARN Happiness School – an event designed to enlighten friends, clients and partners on the subject of happiness and positive psychology.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s event was the biggest yet - with over fifty attendees. Either word has spread, or people feel that now more than ever an extra dose of happiness is required and frankly, who are we to disagree?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EARN Happiness School (EHS) began as an internal project for EARN employees with the mission to ‘make work our happy place’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuelled by the belief that a happier team would equate to a better performing, more creative and productive team – which in turn gives us happier clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/earn-happiness-school-one.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;earn-happiness-school-one.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re certainly not professing to uncover the definitive answer for how to be happy, but we do believe that being mindful of happiness and understanding more about it will lead to a more positive and fulfilling existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far better than us to try to explain the science behind happiness, we have worked with leading positive psychologist &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bridgetgc&quot;&gt;Bridget Grenville-Cleave&lt;/a&gt; to co-create the EARN Happiness School and help develop the accompanying personal happiness tracker app – &lt;a href=&quot;http://howsyourday.today/&quot;&gt;How’s Your Day?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bridget is a firm believer that an individual can control their own happiness: “Research has shown that 60 percent of happiness is determined by our genetics and environment, meaning the remaining 40 percent is up to us. Through improved self-awareness and happiness training, people can become more positive in their outlook and their lives”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, research proves that there is an on-going list of benefits related to happiness that are more than just about ‘feeling good.’ For instance happiness is linked to increased creativity, higher performance, greater resilience, a stronger immune system and even a greater life expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to inspiring and insightful learnings from Bridget, this year we welcomed &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/doctob&quot;&gt;Dr Tim O’Brien&lt;/a&gt; to explore our chosen topic; ‘Is happiness a key factor in high performing teams?’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took us on a philosophical journey to share his view that happiness is a perception, that perception is not reality, and that in fact perception is your filter to reality. It’s a lot to get your head around, but actually when you spend the time considering this philosophy and applying it to your own life, you too start nodding in agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamental to high performing teams is what Tim refers to as a person’s  ‘inner story’ – that is to say what it truly means to be in a team and what each person’s attributes add to create the perfect mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being appreciative of each team member’s inner story is also key. More so acting on everyone’s individual values so they become real behaviours and not just characteristics that are used to describe the overall team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, genuinely understanding the needs within a team is paramount, from the common needs shared amongst everyone to the distinct needs of the individuals. Through this greater understanding and knowledge, teams can build trust and respect - key factors affecting performance. It’s a big topic, and one that is best explained in Tim’s new book ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Inner-Story-Understand-Change-world/dp/1518820476/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1453907655&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=inner\+story&quot;&gt;Inner Story&lt;/a&gt;’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/earn-happiness-school-two.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;earn-happiness-school-two.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to answer the original question, ‘Is happiness a key factor in high performing teams?’ though for now it may be hard to scientifically prove that it is, learning from Tim’s experiences and examples, it unquestionably offers a positive improvement to both individuals and teams as a whole and that’s of great value to any business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download How’s Your Day? in Apple or Play Store – a free personal happiness tracker that helps you monitor, learn and improve your happiness.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://howsyourday.today/&quot;&gt;howsyourday.today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow EARN on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/earn-media-limited&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jamal_benmiloud</name></author><summary>On Monday 26 January (and not just any Monday, the Monday that many refer to as Blue Monday), EARN hosted their annual EARN Happiness School – an event designed to enlighten friends, clients and partners on the subject of happiness and positive psychology.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://earnstudios.com/uploads/earn-happiness-school.jpg" /></entry><entry><title>Brand Love</title><link href="http://earnstudios.com/blog/brand-love/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brand Love" /><published>2016-01-22T13:10:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-01-22T13:10:00+00:00</updated><id>http://earnstudios.com/blog/brand-love</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://earnstudios.com/blog/brand-love/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-build-a-brand-worth-talking-about&quot;&gt;How to build a brand worth talking about&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world where the average customer grows up seeing 170,000 marketing messages by their 17th birthday; where 86% of people admit to sharing social media content in the bathroom; where less than 1% of young people trust advertising; customers only talk about the brands they love. And, if customers aren’t talking about your brand, you might as well not exist. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 18,000,000 photos on Instagram tagged &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/starbucks&quot;&gt;#starbucks&lt;/a&gt;. Not one is paid for by Starbucks. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When Chinese mobile brand Xiaomi launched their new tablet, stock sold out in 2.7 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monster Energy drinks has become the most successful energy drinks brand in the US, without a single dollar spent on advertising &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LEGO continues to defy the expectations of critics and analysts, selling billions of dollars of analog toys in the digital age. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;all-these-stories-are-made-possible-by-brand-love&quot;&gt;All these stories are made possible by Brand Love&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fans don’t just “like” these brands, they love them. And the good news is that it’s neither expensive nor exclusive to cool cutting-edge brands. Brand Love is achievable for all brands. Whether you’re an airline or selling energy drinks, Brand Love is an approach to building a brand worth talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We helped Castrol become the most shared sponsor of the 2014 FIFA World Cup (source Unruly) - our &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/castrol/&quot;&gt;Castrol Footkhana&lt;/a&gt; film grossed 1 million shares and was the most shared film on planet Earth in its  opening week. It’s not just about social media shares either; our approach works in generating hard sales. We collaborated with three of the biggest YouTube superstars to create Limited Edition SIMs that helped EE, the UK’s largest mobile operator, acquire 25,000 new customers overnight. Total sum spent on paid media advertising for both results? = $0.00.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not anti-advertising or paid media, we just believe these investments should come much later on a CMOs’ list to drive share and sales. We recognise that delivering earned impressions are harder to achieve, especially when organic reach through popular social networks is in such fast decline. But why not build your own brand platform for your fans? That’s what we did at Red Bull because when you’re in full control of your ecosystem, no matter how large or small, it’s easier to move consumers from like to love and from customer to ambassador. Red Bull global brand properties such as the Red Bull Air Race, Red Bull Music Academy or Red Bull Racing were far more efficient than traditional sponsorship or advertising. Just type in ‘Red Bull’ to Google and you’ll see the vast earned media this approach produces. As their CEO, Dietrich Mateschitz said, “In literal financial terms, our sports teams are not yet profitable, but in value terms, they are. The total editorial media value plus the media assets created around the teams are superior to pure advertising expenditures”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course not all marketers want to change. There will always be marketers who outsource their work to the same agency because ‘they’ll never get fired for buying media or making a TV ad’. As they say, you can take a horse to water but you can’t make it drink. That’s why we spend our time backing the right horses, the ones that are already thirsty. These are the brave ones that dare to dream big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Brand-Love-Build-Worth-Talking-ebook/dp/B00VBPBU1G&quot;&gt;Brand Love, written by Jamal Benmiloud, Graham Brown and Paul O’Shannessey is available to buy in print or download at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jamal_benmiloud</name></author><summary>How to build a brand worth talking about</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://earnstudios.com/uploads/brand-love-apple.jpg" /></entry><entry><title>Do companies even need creative agencies in the connection economy?</title><link href="http://earnstudios.com/blog/do-companies-even-need-creative-agencies-in-the-connection-economy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do companies even need creative agencies in the connection economy?" /><published>2016-01-22T13:03:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-01-22T13:03:00+00:00</updated><id>http://earnstudios.com/blog/do-companies-even-need-creative-agencies-in-the-connection-economy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://earnstudios.com/blog/do-companies-even-need-creative-agencies-in-the-connection-economy/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;david-ogilvy-revered-as-the-father-of-advertising-was-a-marketing-genius-his-ideas-not-only-shaped-advertising-but-business-in-the-20th-century-his-concepts-were-so-effective-in-the-20th-century-that-they-are-still-paramount-in-how-many-companies-operate-today-but-the-dawn-of-social-media-in-the-21st-century-completely-overturned-the-marketing-landscape-in-which-ogilvys-strategies-flourished&quot;&gt;David Ogilvy, revered as the “Father of Advertising”, was a marketing genius. His ideas not only shaped advertising but business in the 20th century. His concepts were so effective in the 20th century that they are still paramount in how many companies operate today. But the dawn of social media in the 21st century completely overturned the marketing landscape in which Ogilvy’s strategies flourished.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Ogilvy-era the creative agency did all the heavy lifting. They created the brand stories; they decided how brands would play out in the public conscious; they bought media space and spread stories through official, centralised channels. In the Ogilvy-era the goal was to create brand awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal in the Connection Economy is to create Brand Love. Today, everyone is a marketer by default and in most cases they’re more effective than agencies. Previously, people found out about brands through the TV, on the radio or in magazines. Today, they discover new brands through people in their networks sharing their experiences. And people only recommend the brands they love. When a person finds a great new coffee shop they post pictures of it on Instagram or write about it on Facebook and Twitter. At a minimum they tell a friend. Not only are these recommendations shared within their immediate networks, they also travel through the networks of their friends and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Ogilvy-era, agencies were critical because brands were created outside the company, through dog and pony show’s like star-studded launches and publicity stunts. But Brand Love can’t be bought, it has to be earned. And brands need to be developed from the inside out. 
There are three fundamentals to building Brand Love: people, culture and metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-brand-love-model&quot;&gt;The Brand Love Model&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&quot;people-companies-need-people-on-their-team-who-get-it-they-need-people-who-love-interacting-they-need-to-recruit-empathetic-people-with-the-same-passions-as-their-fans&quot;&gt;People. Companies need people on their team who “get it”. They need people who love interacting. They need to recruit empathetic people with the same passions as their fans.&lt;/h5&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&quot;culture-companies-need-to-create-cultures-that-encourage-fans-to-interact-with-each-other-as-well-as-the-company&quot;&gt;Culture. Companies need to create cultures that encourage fans to interact with each other as well as the company.&lt;/h5&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&quot;metrics-companies-need-to-use-metrics-that-encourage-relationship-building&quot;&gt;Metrics. Companies need to use metrics that encourage relationship building.&lt;/h5&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, back to the question at hand: “Do companies even need creative agencies in The Connection Economy?” Well, we can’t really answer that question with a simple yes or no. But we can say that no matter how much you spend on advertising, social media or product launches, your brand will always gravitate back towards the experience created by your People, Culture and Metrics. So if you’re going to work with an agency make sure you work with one that understands The Brand Love Model and that will work with you (not on your behalf) to co-create fan-centric products, experiences and content platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jamal_benmiloud</name></author><summary>David Ogilvy, revered as the “Father of Advertising”, was a marketing genius. His ideas not only shaped advertising but business in the 20th century. His concepts were so effective in the 20th century that they are still paramount in how many companies operate today. But the dawn of social media in the 21st century completely overturned the marketing landscape in which Ogilvy’s strategies flourished.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://earnstudios.com/uploads/castrol.jpg" /></entry></feed>
